269-599-9811 nik.kaczka@kaczka.us

Dedicated Naval Officer with 12 years of experience in various roles, developing multiple managerial and leadership skills in extremely technical fields. Facilitated training and mentored junior sailors on the proper use of cryptologic tools and techniques. Developed valuable experience in program management, senior executive staff responsibilities, and resource management.

# **Professional Experience**

### U.S. NAVY

## **December 2012 – Present**

## **Program Administrator**

September 2023 - Present

- Coordinated force generation inputs from across multiple directorates and delivered results to senior executive decision makers, supporting global initiatives.
- Delivered key information to senior executives to support decision making at the highest levels, affecting global operations.
- Initiated reporting requirements for subordinate organizations.
- Organized cross-organizational working groups at the senior executive level.
- Contributed to the design and creation of a performance validation and evaluation program, implemented globally.

# **Project Manager**

August 2021 - August 2023

Navy and Marine Corps Commendation Medal Armed Forces Service Medal

- Managed 11 departments in an industrial project, including process training, process improvement, scheduling project tasks, and coordinating resources, keeping the organization 12% ahead of schedule.
- Managed material maintenance program, including training and qualifications.
- Led the collection of key data points for analysis of trends, increasing readiness of the organization.
- Streamlined data collection processes, reducing the number of man-hours required by 75%.
- Directed a cross functional team comprised of 100+ personnel in the safety and security of material, personnel, and organizational infrastructure. Conducted weekly, practical training to enhance the capability of the cross functional team.

### **Deputy Division Chief**

September 2018 - June 2021

Joint Service Commendation Medal

- Managed 70+ diverse personnel in the collection and analysis of key datasets, resulting in hundreds of reports to senior executives in multiple international organizations, supporting executive decision making processes.
- Implemented an improved training plan that filled gaps in training, resulting an improvement in effectiveness of 70% and increased personnel qualifications during a global pandemic.

- Built a division of 30+ diverse personnel after a company reorganization.
- Rebuilt a federally mandated program, including rewriting company policy and procedures in accordance with updated regulations.

#### **Naval Aviator**

December 2014 - June 2018

- Led a small team in creating daily operations schedules to accomplish long term objectives, coordinating requirements, personnel, and equipment.
- Led a division in maintaining aviation airframes and equipment, safely executing daily flight schedules with a 100% success rate.
- Executed hundreds of flight hours, managing flight crews, and executing various procedures and processes to earn various aviation qualifications.
- Managed qualification program for junior employees, resulting in numerous qualifications earned; increasing employee availability and squadron capabilities.

### **Student Naval Aviator**

December 2012 - December 2014

#### **Education**

**Master's in Computer Science** June 2023 - Present **Old Dominion University at Norfolk, VA** 

**Bachelor's in Electrical Engineering** June 2008 - December 2012 **Miami University of Ohio at Oxford, OH** 

## **Key Competencies**

- Detail Oriented
- Microsoft Office Suite
- Adaptable

- Analytical Thinking
- Results-Driven

## **Certificates**

#### **Pilot Certification**

- Private Fixed Wing
- Private Rotary Wing
- Commercial Fixed Wing
- Commercial Rotary Wing
- Instrument Rated Fixed Wing
- Instrument Rated Rotary Wing